// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following is the largest district (area wise) of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "Lahaul and Spiti",
    options: [
      "Lahaul and Spiti",
      "Shimla",
      "Sirmaur",
      "ChambaSS"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The Chail cricket stadium is located in which district of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "Solan",
    options: [
      "Una",
      " Solan",
      "Shimla",
      "Kangra"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following mountain pass lies in Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "Kangra",
    options: [
      "Kangra",
      " Solan",
      "Mandi",
      "Chamba"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "In which year Amar Singh Thapa beseiged Kangra Fort?",
    answer: "1805",
    options: [
      "1809",
      "1805",
      "1804",
      "1803",
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Where was the Gandhi-Irwin pact signed?",
    answer: "Shimla ",
    options: [
      "kangra",
      " Chamba",
      "Dalhousie",
      "Shimla "
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The Pandoh Dam is located on which river in Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "Beas River",
    options: [
      "Chenab River",
      "Ravi River",
      "Beas River",
      "Yamuna River"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Who was chosen as the president of the provisional government of Himachal Pradesh formed in 1948?",
    answer: "Sadanand Chande",
    options: [
      "Kanshi Ram",
      "Sadanand Chande",
      "Y S Parmar",
      "Krishnanand"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following district of Himachal Pradesh is known as “Chhota Kashi”?",
    answer: "Mandi",
    options: [
      "Mandi",
      "kullu",
      "chamba",
      "kangra"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In which year Amar Singh Thapa beseiged Kangra Fort?",
    answer: "1805",
    options: [
      "1804",
      "1805",
      "1801",
      "1815"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The water of Kareri Lake in Dharamshala falls into which of the following rivers?",
    answer: "Layun",
    options: [
      "Bhaga",
      "chakki",
      "Layun",
      "chandra"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "In which district is Gauri Devi ka Tibba peak located?",
    answer: "Chamba ",
    options: [
      "kangra",
      " Chamba",
      "Dalhousie",
      "Shimla "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Where in Himachal Pradesh Satluj river enters?",
    answer: "Shipki  ",
    options: [
      "Shipki ",
      " Namgia",
      "Karcham",
      "Keylong "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Beas river meets river Satluj at which of the following places?",
    answer: "Hari ka Patan ",
    options: [
      "kangra",
      " Hari ka Patan",
      " Mirthal",
  
      "Katrain "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Who was the founder of Suket state?",
    answer: "Vir Sen ",
    options: [
      "han Sen",
      " Ban Sen",
      "Tan Sen",
      "Vir Sen "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Who was the founder of Brahmpur state?",
    answer: "Meru Verman ",
    options: [
      "hari Verman",
      " Ram Verman",
      "Meru Verman",
      "Kumar Verman"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "In which year were the first elections to Vidhan Sabha held in Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "1951",
    options: [
      "1954",
      " 1951",
      "1957",
      "1955 "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Who was the first governor of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: " S Chakravarti",
    options: [
      "S Chakravarti",
      "Y S Parmar",
      "Thakur Ram Singh",
      "E. Penderal Moon"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Nargu sanctuary is located in which district of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "Mandi ",
    options: [
      "kangra",
      " Chamba",
      "Dalhousie",
      "Mandi "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which is the only sanctuary in Himachal Pradesh reporting the presence of Kashmir Stag?",
    answer: "Gamgul Siahbehi Sanctuary ",
    options: [
      "Gamgul Siahbehi Sanctuary",
      " Kanawar Sanctuary",
      "Kalatope Khajjiar Sanctuary",
      " Gamgul Siahbehi Sanctuary "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which of the following districts of Himachal Pradesh is located on the international border of india?",
    answer: "kinnaur",
    options: [
      "kinnaur",
      " Chamba",
      "Dalhousie",
      "Shimla "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "Who introduced Buddhism in the Lahaul Spiti district of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "Padmasambhan",
    options: [
      " Padmanand",
      "Padmabhushan",
      "Padmasambhan",
      "E. Penderal Moon"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "Pin Valley National Park is located in which district of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: " Lahaul Spiti",
    options: [
      "chamba",
      " Lahaul Spiti",
      "kangra",
      "mandi"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Which was the first Capital of Nurpur State?",
    answer: " Pathan Kot",
    options: [
      "Pathan Kot",
      "shahpur",
      "trigarta",
      "niyajpur"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "The longest river of Himachal Pradesh is",
    answer: "  Satluj",
    options: [
      "Jehlem",
      "Chenab",
      " Beas",
      " Satluj"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "When were many areas of Punjab merged with Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: " 1966",
    options: [
      "1966",
      "1961",
      "1964",
      "1965"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "What is the area of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: "21,495 sq. mi",
    options: [
      "24,495 sq. mi",
      "21,495 sq. mi",
      "25,495 sq. mi",
      "27,495 sq. mi"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "Himachal Pradesh came into being on 15th April 1948 and had four districts. At that time which one among the following districts was not the part of Himachal?",
    answer: "Bilaspur ",
    options: [
      "Bilaspur",
      "Chamba",
      "sirmaur",
      "kangra"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "Which one is is the largest district by area wise in Himachal Pradesh",
    answer: "  Lahaul and Spiti",
    options: [
      "kinnaur",
      "Kangra",
      "Shimla",
      " Lahaul and Spiti"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "Mukkila Glacier is located in which one of the following regions?",
    answer: " Bhaga Valley",
    options: [
      "Bhaga Valley",
      "Pangi",
      "Manali",
      "Rohru"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "Who was the founder of Theog princely state?",
    answer: " Jai Chand",
    options: [
      " Ram Chand",
      "Jai Chand",
      "Veer chand",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 31,
    question: "Manikaran hot water springs' are present in which district of Himachal Pradesh?",
    answer: " Kullu",
    options: [
      "Kullu",
      "Kangra",
      "Mandi",
      "Chamba"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 32,
    question: "Who was the first governor-general of India to visit Shimla?",
    answer: " Lord Amherst",
    options: [
      "Lord Amherst",
      "Lord Mayo",
      "Lord Cornwallis",
      "Lord Dalhousie"
    ]
  },



  {
    numb: 33,
    question: "The State Day of Himachal Pradesh is",
    answer: " 5th April",
    options: [
      "15th January",
      "5th April",
      "5 March",
      "21 March"
    ]
  },


  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];